GORDON SNURR

(301) 697-5862 | gsnurr3@hotmail.com

Portfolio: http://www.gordonsnurr.com/

Professional Summary

During my time in the technology field, I have gained experience in software development, IT support, and customer service. I have both a Public Trust and Interim Secret Clearance. I also have obtained my Comptia Security+ and I am certified in Agile (SCRUM) as well. My primary focus and experience has been Java and Java related frameworks, including front-end experience, such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and more. I am committed to my studies at all times in order to keep advancing my current skill set and learn new ones.

Work History

Java Developer (Mid-Level)

06/2018 to Current

ACI Federal – Fort Knox, KY

- Front-end: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JSP, Spring Tags, JavaScript, JSTL, jQuery, Apache Tiles, Thymeleaf
- Back-end: Java, SpringMVC, SpringBoot, Spring Security, JPA, Hibernate, JDBC Template, JUnit, SQL, SOAP Services, REST Services
- Other: Linux (Fedora), Maven, JBoss, Apache Tomcat, NetBeans, SOAPUI, Postman, Apache Subversion,
 DbVisualizer, Caliber
- Documentation: Unit Test Plan, Code Peer Review, Document Component Architecture
- Methodologies: Waterfall, Mix (Waterfall/Agile)

Application Development Specialist

01/2016 to 01/2018

IBM - Rocket Center, WV

- Front-end: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JSP, Spring Tags, JavaScript, JSTL, jQuery, AngularJS
- Back-end: Java, SpringMVC, NoSQL (Cloudant)
- Other: Maven, Oracle Weblogic, Apache Tomcat, Eclipse, NetBeans, SOAPUI, Postman, Rational ClearCase, Rational ClearQuest, Rational Team Concert, HPE Fortify Security
- Documentation: Unit Test Plan, Code Peer Review
- Methodologies: Agile SCRUM, Waterfall, Mix (Waterfall/Agile)

IT Help Desk Specialist II

06/2011 to 09/2016

Western Maryland Health Systems – Cumberland, MD

- Managed user accounts within Active Directory, Meditech, and several other applications.
- Resolved problems with malfunctioning products (50+ different applications, hardware, and network related)

- Researched, troubleshot and resolved complex problems independently.
- Reviewed technical documentation and procedures.
- Installed software, modified and repaired hardware and resolved technical issues.
- Used ticketing systems to manage and process actions taken.
- Demonstrated professionalism and courtesy with customers at all times.
- Managed call flow and responded to technical support needs of customers.
- Referred major hardware and software problems and defective products to vendors or technicians for service.
- Trained users in the proper use of hardware or software.
- Used scripts to contribute to financial department.
- Trained new IT Help Desk employees.

Partner and iOS Application Developer

06/2013 to 06/2014

Judgment Entertainment - Ridgeley, WV

- Released application called "Mouse in the House" on iOS store for current iPhones and iPads at the time.
- Responsible for features, such as Game Center, In-App Purchasing, Facebook sync, UI, Core Data (Local Database), and audio.
- Wrote maintainable and extensible code in a team environment with Objective-C and Xcode.
- Wrote contract, hired, and worked along graphical designers for application requirements.
- Documented design and requirements of application, including a request for proposal.
- Managed company financials and documentation.
- Collaborated with project team daily to give status and discuss requirements.
- Updated application with GitHub.

Information Technology Intern

03/2010 to 07/2010

Orbital ATK - Keyser, WV

- Managed user accounts with Active Directory.
- Troubleshot hardware and software issues within a timely manner.
- Spoke with clients daily, documented issue, fixed issue, and documented the resolution.
- Setup new hardware and software for clients.
- Documented and assigned escalated work items to proper personnel.

Education

Bachelor of Science: Software Engineering

2016

University Of Phoenix - Tempe, AZ

Other education:

- Comptia Security+
- ICAgile Certified Professional (ICP)
- Learn Java Unit Testing with JUnit 5 in 20 Steps

- Learn Linux in 5 Days and Level Up Your Career
- Struts 2 Framework for Beginners
- Spring & Hibernate for Beginners (includes SpringBoot)
- Master Hibernate and JPA with Spring Boot in 100 Steps
- Build Responsive Real World Websites with HTML5 and CSS3
- Learn and Understand NodeJS
- The Complete SQL Bootcamp
- The Complete JavaScript Course: Build a Real-World Project
- Global Blue Consulting

Accomplishments

- Received October 2018 Employee of the Month from ACI Federal.
- Promoted at IBM from band 6A to 6B and received performance recognition from 2 project assessments, 2 managers, and 10 statements submitted by co-workers on various projects.
- Promoted at Western Maryland Health Systems from Help Desk Technician, to Help Desk Specialist, and then to Help Desk Specialist II.

Security Clearances

- Public Trust
- Interim Secret